# **Gregory Witek**

hello@gwitek.com +31 (0) 6 39 87 70 17 Amsterdam, Netherlands

### **PROFILE**

I am an ambitious and product-oriented engineering manager with 15 years of experience. I've worked across various domains, including infrastructure, travel, and fintech. I combine deep technical expertise and strong management skills to help engineering teams achieve their goals.

### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

# 04/2022 — currently: Senior Engineering Manager at Booking.com

- Led a group of 3 engineering managers and 15 engineers in platform engineering department
- Oversaw areas like Internal Developer Portal, incident response, secrets management, engineering excellence, and site reliability
- Led contract negotiations with multiple vendors, resulting in multi-million dollar agreements
- Co-created internal career framework for engineering managers
- Worked closely with SREs across the company to improve incident response and post mortem processes
- Reduced time to create new internal UIs from months to days by introducing a new Internal Developer Portal
- Overhauled internal software catalog consisting of more than 10,000 software components
- Supported growth of managers and individual contributors, led multiple successful promotion cases

## 08/2021 - 04/2022: Engineering Manager at Booking.com

- Led an engineering team responsible for building tools supporting site reliability
- Introduced a company-wide on-call policy, onboarded 3,000+ engineers across multiple countries
- Improved team processes, reduced technical debt, and increased team productivity

## 10/2020 - 08/2021: Engineering Manager at EclecticIQ

- Led a cross-functional team of 10 members, including developers, testers, and technical writers
- Led development of Threat Intelligence platform used by companies and governments across the world
- Overhauled team processes, including 1-1s, capacity planning, and retrospectives, to enhance productivity
- Guided the team through a challenging period marked by resignations, leadership uncertainty, and low customer satisfaction

## 09/2019 - 09/2020: Engineering Manager at Diligent

- Led two hybrid teams, with 11 direct reports
- Introduced modern software development practices: reduced the release cycle from 3 months to 1 week, increased test coverage, improved code quality with regular code reviews
- Established regular 1-1s and set personal objectives for team members

• Delivered multiple features supporting corporate governance platform

# 07/2017 - 12/2018: Head of Engineering at Ascenda (Singapore)

- Managed three engineering teams, overseeing up to 16 direct reports
- Introduced remote-first culture across the company
- Built the first overseas team in Manila, Philippines selected location and hired engineers
- Led the implementation of a fintech product used by major banks and airlines across the world
- Overhauled team structure and processes to accommodate growth
- Continued to be a hands-on engineer, with around 20% of time dedicated to programming

# 11/2014 - 07/2017: Lead Software Engineer at Ascenda (Singapore)

- Designed and led implementation of a multi-tenant travel platform in Ruby and JavaScript
- Built a robust and scalable hotel search engine using Elixir
- Integrated 100+ APIs: hotel providers, payments, loyalty programs of airlines and banks
- Developed two open source Ruby gems to streamline the management of business logic and multi-tenant configuration

## 10/2009 - 11/2014: Software developer at various companies

- Worked as a software developer for companies in Poland, Spain, Germany, and Singapore
- Worked in various domains including e-commerce, adtech, and fintech
- Led multiple workshops, internship programs, and supported management in hiring developers
- Presented at a number of local meet-ups and international conferences

#### SKILLS

- Programming languages: JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Elixir, Java
- Domains: distributed systems, incident response, developer experience, SaaS, product development
- Management: leadership, project management, technical strategy, mentoring, coaching, problem solving, critical thinking, team building, performance management

## **EDUCATION**

Poznan University of Technology: BSc in Computer Science, 2007 – 2011

Poznan University of Technology: MSc in Computer Science, 2011 – 2012

### VOLUNTEERING

- Shared my knowledge and experience on my blog and YouTube channel, Not Only Code
- Supported initiatives like TechLadies and Rails Girls as a programming coach
- Mentored engineers and managers through non-profit platforms, Upnotch and Mentoring Club
- Spoke at several international conferences, including EuRuKo (Greece), WebExpo Prague (Czechia), RedDotRuby (Singapore), RubyConf Taiwan, and more
- Co-organized community meet-ups: PRUG in Poland, RubySG and Elixir User Group in Singapore